Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Oversize materials, 1872-1988; MS0125 Series 10; 1 Linear foot
  - Photocopy of Honorary Degree of humane Letters given to Cunliffe from New England College (Henniker, New Hampshire), 05/06/1979 (Oversize 98, Folder 15)
  - Souvenir booklet from the "Circle" - group of Cunliffe's friends/Fellows, including photos, 1958 ca. (Oversize 98, Folder 16)
  - Poster from KIX FM 106 Country radio of George Washington in a cowboy hat, 02/1982 (Oversize 98, Folder 17)
- Books written and edited by Marcus Cunliffe, 1958-1987; MS0125 Series 11; 2 Linear feet
  This series consists of 2 boxes (2.0 linear feet) of books written and edited by Cunliffe from 1958-1987. These include George Washington Man and Monument, American Presidents and the Presidency, Chattel Slavery and Wage Slavery, Soldiers and Civilians The Martial Spirit in America 1775-1865, The Literature of the United States. Also included are some of his books translated into Spanish, Italian, and French.
  - The Age of Expansion, 1848-1917. London: Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - American Presidents and the Presidency. New York: American Heritage Press, 1972 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - American Presidents and the Presidency. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode Publishers Ltd., 1969 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - American Presidents and the Presidency. 2nd ed. New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1976 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Chattel Slavery and Wage Slavery: The Anglo-American Context, 1830-1860. Athens: The University of Georgia Press, 1979 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - George Washington Man and Monument. Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1958 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - George Washington Man and Monument. London: Collins Saint James, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - George Washington Man and Monument. New York: The New American Library, Inc., 1982 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - The Literature of the United States. 4th ed. New York: Penguin Books, 1986 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - The Literature of the United States. New York: Penguin Books, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - The Nation Takes Shape, 1789-1837. Chicago: University Chicago Press, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe Marcus and Robin Winks, Eds. Pastmasters Some Essays on American Historians. 1st ed. New York: Harper & Row Publishers, 1969 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus and Robin Winks, Eds. Pastmasters Some Essays on American Historians. New York: Harper & Row Publishers, 1975 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. The Presidency. 3rd ed. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1987 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Soldiers and Civilians The Martial Spirit in America, 1775-1865 Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1968 (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. Sphere History of Literature in the English Language vol. 8 American Literature to 1900. London: Barrie & Jenkins Ltd., 1973 (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. Sphere History of Literature in the English Language vol. 8 American Literature since 1900. London: Sphere Books Limited 1975. (Paperback), undated (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. Sphere History of Literature in the English Language vol. 9 American Literature since 1900. London: Barrie & Jenkins Ltd. 1975. (2 copies), undated (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. Sphere History of Literature in the English Language vol. 9 American Literature since 1900. London: Sphere Books Limited 1975.(Paperback), undated (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. Sphere History of Literature: American Literature since 1900 London: Sphere Books Limited, 1986 (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - Weems, Mason L. Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. The Life of Washington. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Weems, Mason L. Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. The Life of Washington. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 22)
  - Weems, Mason L. Cunliffe, Marcus, Ed. The Life of Washington. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1976 (Box 99, Folder 23)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, George Washington Hombre Y Procer. Argentina: Plaza & Janes, S.A., 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. George Washington l'homme et la legende. Paris: Editions Seghers, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Historia Da Literatura Dos Estados Unidos. Portugal: Publicacoes Europa-America, Lda., 1986 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Historija Knjizevnosti S.A.D. Rijeka: Penguin Books, 1959 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. La Litterature des Etats-Unis. Paris: Presses Universitaires de France, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Storia Della Letteratura Americana. Torino: Piccolo Biblioteca Einaudi, Tomo primo, 1958 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Storia Della Letteratura Americana. Torino: Piccolo Biblioteca Einaudi, Tomo secondo, 1958 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus. Storia Della Letteratura Americana. Giulio Einaudi ed., 1958 (Box 100, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous materials, undated; MS0125 Series 12; 2.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of note cards containing bibliographic information on books and journal articles on various research subjects, including U.S. military history and American literature. Also present are home and business addresses of colleagues. This series also includes approximately 225 lantern slides and 5 reels of microfilm There is one box of restricted letters of reference and recommendation that Cunliffe wrote for students, which will remain closed until 2066, unless permission is granted from the donor to view select files.
  - Note cards containing bibliographic info on books and journal articles on various research subjects, including U.S. military history, American literature. Also contains home and business addresses of colleagues, undated (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Note cards (continued from Box 101), James Family, Heroism; Lantern slides (approx. 225), and microfilm. Film titled: Frederick Jackson Turner and the Frontier (2 reels), undated (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Parson Weems biography, 1960 (2 reels), Sarah Anne Dorsey (1940), Military magazine selections, Gen. Wool controversy. Also contains a few business cards from Cunliffe's GW career, undated (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Letters of recommendation for students, 1983 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Letters of reference written by Cunliffe, 1983-1986 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Letters of reference for students and colleagues re fellowships/grants-- A to L, 1984-1988 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Letters of reference for students and colleagues re fellowships/grants-- A to L, 1982-1986 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Letters of reference for students and colleagues re fellowships/grants-- A to L, 1982-1986 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Letters of reference for students and colleagues re fellowships/grants-- M to Z, 1981-1990 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Letters of reference for students and colleagues re fellowships/grants-- M to Z, 1981-1987 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Master's degree student Angie Spicer, 1986 (Box 103, Folder 8)